<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-03-05T16:17:02-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Dilpreet Kaur</title><subtitle>
This blog is about the basic elements of design thinking and making  interfaces easy to use.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Prototyping-With-Invision</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/Prototyping-With-Invision" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prototyping-With-Invision" /><published>2018-02-11T17:08:38-08:00</published><updated>2018-02-11T17:08:38-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/Prototyping-with-Invision</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/Prototyping-With-Invision">&lt;div class=&quot;ex00&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/invision.svg&quot; alt=&quot;img/svg&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- Content --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prototyping is one of the most important stages of a design process. It allows a designer to check and test all the design decisions he/she made during UX process. Prototypes should not be compared to the final product, rather these are the samples which are only built to test the functionality of the app. Before starting the Interface Design, it is crucial for a designer to test all the design solutions which will save time and effort in the end. Testing with prototypes will reveal all the basic bugs in your design prior to the actual implementation and you can fix them beforehand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;General Description of the tool&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invision is a prototyping software which provides a number of digital interactions with the still mockups of an interface. It also supports designing user interfaces for mobile applications. It is one of the major players in the market as it constantly improves the user experience but also regularly add extensions to the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Invision provides the ability to upload more or less detailed wireframes and with the functionalities of the app these wireframes are converted into the prototype. Invision makes it very easy to input the necessary transitions, test the navigation and analyze button behaviours which is important to test prior to the development process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As per developer’s perspective, Invision allows better collaboration between designers and developers. Rather than documenting the necessary transition effects and hover behaviours, a designer can visually let the developer know about the effects that clearly bridges the gap between both parties.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;h2&gt;Steps towards your first prototype with invision&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sign In to Invision if you are already a user otherwise sign up.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;For the first time, Invision allows to create a new project under which you can choose to prototype, create mood-boards or draw freehand. Choose ‘create new prototype’.&lt;/li&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;listimg&quot;&gt;


	&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/start.svg&quot; alt=&quot;img/svg&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Enter your project name and choose whether its a mobile app or web app.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;listimg&quot;&gt;


		&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/start2.svg&quot; alt=&quot;img/svg&quot;&gt;
	
	&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Now upload all of your screen mockups or you can also drag/drop. You can also upload loading screen of your app. Loading screen is the screen which will be visible while launching your app.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;listimg&quot;&gt;


		&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/upload.svg&quot; alt=&quot;img/svg&quot;&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You can start by clicking your first mockup or where you want the interaction to start. Here, I will start with my LogIn Page.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;listimg&quot;&gt;


		&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/view.svg&quot; alt=&quot;img/svg&quot;&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The next screen will show your mock in a mobile interface. This is automatically in the ‘Preview Mode’. In order to start prototyping, make sure you switch to ‘Build Mode’.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;listimg&quot;&gt;


		&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/mode.svg&quot; alt=&quot;img/svg&quot;&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;li&gt;When you enter the Build Mode, you can start creating hotspots. Hotspots are the areas of the where your user will actually click and interact with the app. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;listimg&quot;&gt;


		&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/hotspot.svg&quot; alt=&quot;img/svg&quot;&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;li&gt;A dialog box will appear which will ask you to input all the important information like the destination where you want your user to end up after clicking the particular button, gesture with the button and what sort of transition would you like. Enter all the necessary information and press ‘Save’.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;listimg&quot;&gt;


		&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/hinfo.svg&quot; alt=&quot;img/svg&quot;&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;li&gt;You can Shift+Click on the created hotspot to navigate in the Build Mode which will take you to the chosen destination. Here you can create another hotspot and repeat the previous step on all the other screens to create a navigation for your app.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;listimg&quot;&gt;


		&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/click.svg&quot; alt=&quot;img/svg&quot;&gt;
	
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Above steps were just the basic steps to start with Invision. There are so many other functionalities of Invision that will help you prototype better and share it with your fellow designers and developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you explore the exciting new features of the app &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.invisionapp.com/new-features&quot;&gt; here&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Simplicity in Design</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blogs/Simplicity-in-design" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Simplicity in Design" /><published>2018-01-26T17:08:38-08:00</published><updated>2018-01-26T17:08:38-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blogs/first-post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blogs/Simplicity-in-design">&lt;div class=&quot;ex00&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/ex00.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;img/jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;!-- Content --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplicity is by far the most ironical concept in terms of design. This irony is clearly expressed by famous Paul Rand’s quote, &lt;i&gt;“Design is so simple, that’s why it’s complicated”.&lt;/i&gt;  As human beings, we want our things to be simple to use. We are entitled to get annoyed by the things that are confusing. How many times do you think about what button to press while using a lift? Or pushing or pulling a door which has no clear sign on it. We can think of millions of examples from our daily life which states this concept.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simplicity doesn’t always mean to reduce colours and increase white space in your design. Simplicity should be understood more in terms of user experience because ultimately you are designing for someone else. So in easy terms, &lt;b&gt;simplicity is something that makes the interface easy to use for the audience&lt;/b&gt;. It directly depends on what your client wants to achieve with the specific piece of software.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

	For example, your client wants you to design an app which can control your tv’s volume and change channels. The ultimate goal of your client is controlling volume and switch between channels. But this happens:

&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;ex01&quot;&gt;

	&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/ex01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img/jpg&quot;&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
	This design may look simple to the designer but as per user’s perspective, this can be the most complicated thing to explore. So, it is very important for designers to understand the concept of simplicity in terms of user experience.

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;5 ways to achieve simplicity in your Designs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;1.&amp;nbsp Understand your users&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the first and foremost step when we start the designing process. We do all the interviews required to understand what our client wants. Instead of asking the basic questions like what features they want, ask them about their imagination about the app. Ask them why achieving certain goals through this app is important for them. When a designer is able to find the emotion behind the user’s need, half of the design job is done there. &lt;/p&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;2. &amp;nbspAvoid adding unnecessary features&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After interviewing the user, we may have the potential list of features that our client wants in their app. As designers, we must stick to the scope of the project. You may have other additional things in your mind that may be suitable for the app but you should always stick to what your client wants and expect from this app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to an interesting psychological concept called the paradox of choice, the more choices we have, the less happy we are with the choices that we make. Adding new features to the interface always feel good but overloading your app with unnecessary features will always confuse the users and they wont be able to perform basic functions of that very app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;3.&amp;nbspIncrease white space&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I said earlier, don’t mistake simplicity with white space in your design but it can be considered as an asset which will help you achieve simplicity in your design. Whenever a user sees enough breathing space in the elements of the design, things look simpler in the brain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, why do people often say Google it instead of Bing it. The answer is simple. Google provide such simplicity on the landing page that there are no unnecessary distractions and a lot of white space. Users find it very clear in their brains about what actions to perform over there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;timg&quot;&gt;
	
	&lt;div class=&quot;bing&quot;&gt;

		&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/bing.png&quot; alt=&quot;img/jpg&quot;&gt;

	&lt;/div&gt;

	&lt;div class=&quot;google&quot;&gt;

		&lt;img src=&quot;../../assets/google.png&quot; alt=&quot;img/jpg&quot;&gt;

	&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;4.&amp;nbspMaintain hierarchy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As designers, it is our responsibility to guide users to perform specific actions on the app. You can manipulate the visual perception of your users. You should always be clear about what do you want your users to see first. There are multiple ways with which you can maintain hierarchy in your designs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Understand the page scanning patterns available these days. Recent studies have shown that people first scan a page to get a sense of whether they are interested, before committing to read it. You can study in detail about these patterns in this famous article by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/f-shaped-pattern-reading-web-content/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Neilson Norman Group&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;It is a psychological fact that human beings tend to read bigger things first. So, if you want your user to read a certain thing first, use big typography.&lt;/li&gt;

	&lt;li&gt;You can also achieve good hierarchy by choosing right colour, texture and effect for a particular element of the design.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;


	&lt;h3&gt;5.&amp;nbspRight use of typography&lt;/h3&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Typography plays a major role in explaining your users about the interface and guiding them through the entire process of performing a specific action on that interface. So choosing the right typography and being consistent with it for the entire interface are important things to consider for achieving simplicity. Exploring visual aspects of type can make your design really shout. It can effect the readers’ moods and emotions and evoke reactions.&lt;/p&gt; 

	&lt;p&gt;The biggest example of the importance of right typography in your design is when the wrong winner was declared at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.slate.com/blogs/browbeat/2017/02/27/moonlight_wins_best_picture_as_incredible_twist_ending_makes_2017_oscars.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;2017 Academy Awards&lt;/a&gt; for the best picture. As you can clearly see in the picture that the the most important thing is “Best Picture” which is written at the bottom of the card and in the tiniest font and it is very hard to see. Even the wrong envelope was handed to the announcers, if they could have see the category clearly, the chaos would have been avoided.&lt;/p&gt;

	&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>